<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Palate Deck</title>
    <description>Better Beer Tasting Tools
</description>
    <link>http://palatedeck.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://palatedeck.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2016 11:46:33 -0700</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2016 11:46:33 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.1.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Introducing the Palate Deck</title>
        <description>&lt;img src=&quot;/images/photo-pd-intro.jpg&quot; class=&quot;blog-photo&quot; alt=&quot;Hand holding Palate Deck Cards&quot;&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Stop me if any of this sounds familiar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You&#39;re out having pints of your favorite local IPA, and for some reason it tastes a lot sharper and rougher than usual.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or, maybe you&#39;re splitting a bottle of saison with a few friends and you&#39;ve all noticed a distinct spiciness you&#39;re all trying to find the right word to describe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or perhaps you&#39;re sampling your way through a flight at a new local brewery, and there&#39;s something not quite right about their golden ale... but you can&#39;t put your finger on it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&#39;ve all had beer-drinking experiences like these. Maybe you&#39;ll get lucky and have a knowledgeable server who can help you diagnose what you&#39;re tasting, but when you&#39;re on your own how do you get to the bottom of your pint glass, so to speak?&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;h2 class=&quot;heading-secondary&quot;&gt;Learning Beer&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I barely need to mention how popular craft beer is right now. People care about what they&#39;re eating and drinking more than ever, and they want to drink better beer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those same people are increasingly interested in having a basic literacy of the flavors and aromas they&#39;re experiencing in various beer styles. The problem is that there&#39;s not much out there to help you understand what you&#39;re tasting when you drink.&lt;/p&gt; 

&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s true that many existing beer books and courses are geared toward the brewing process, beer history, and the ingredients you&#39;d use when making beer. But where do you turn if you want to start with the flavors in your glass &lt;em&gt;right now&lt;/em&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is what the Palate Deck is about.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class=&quot;heading-secondary&quot;&gt;How does it work?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyone already knows plenty about culinary and beverage terms for basic tastes and smells, thanks to the fact we&#39;re conscious humans who consume food and drink. These are the closest thing we have to a universal when it comes to describing what we taste, and they can absolutely be applied to beer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;blog-image-right&quot; src=&quot;/images/cards-example.png&quot; alt=&quot;Cards with the words Hoppy, Floral, Fruity&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What the Palate Deck offers is a starting point. It creates a structure for your conversation and a cheat sheet for your beer vocabulary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On each card you&#39;ll find a word, and a lot of ways of describing that word. Players consider these, discard the ones that don&#39;t match, and talk about the ones they think might apply. You match terms you&#39;re already familiar with to the beer you&#39;re drinking, which allows you to learn more about both your beer and your preferences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;/about/&quot;&gt;more to it&lt;/a&gt; of course, but that&#39;s the quick summary of how it works.  And if you really want to know what&#39;s causing something in your beer, there&#39;s extra information on each card to give you some context about why you&#39;re experiencing that flavor or aroma.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;h2 class=&quot;heading-secondary&quot;&gt;Who&#39;s behind it?&lt;/h2&gt;

  &lt;figure class=&quot;media media-right&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;media-img media-img-large&quot;&gt;
      &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/mezzoblue/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/photo-brewday.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;

    &lt;figcaption class=&quot;media-caption&quot;&gt;
  		&lt;p&gt;Hi, I’m &lt;a href=&quot;http://daveshea.com/&quot;&gt;Dave&lt;/a&gt;. I’ve spent almost 20 years in the technology world, but outside of my day job I’ve been interested in the beer industry for a long while now.&lt;/p&gt;

  		&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve been homebrewing since 2010 and I&#39;ve had the opportunity to brew commercially a few times. I run the annual &lt;a href=&quot;http://farmhousefest.com/&quot;&gt;Farmhouse Fest&lt;/a&gt; beer festival in Vancouver, and over the past couple of years I’ve become a Certified BJCP beer judge and a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cicerone.org/us-en/users/dave-shea-0&quot;&gt;Certified Cicerone®&lt;/a&gt;, which are things you probably don&#39;t care about unless you&#39;re in the beer industry, but trust me they&#39;re pretty cool.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;



&lt;h2 class=&quot;heading-secondary&quot;&gt;When can you buy it?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You&#39;ll get your first chance to buy the Palate Deck when the Kickstarter campaign launches during the first two weeks of October. Follow along on &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/thepalatedeck&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/palatedeck&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; to hear about it, or &lt;a href=&quot;/buy/&quot;&gt;sign up&lt;/a&gt; for a one-time email when the campaign goes live.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2016 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://palatedeck.com/2016/09/23/intro.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://palatedeck.com/2016/09/23/intro.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Beer Glassware</title>
        <description>&lt;img src=&quot;/images/photo-alibi2.jpg&quot; class=&quot;blog-photo&quot; alt=&quot;Different beer glassware&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beer glassware is one of those subjects that many will roll their eyes at, and with good reason. Six-packs comes in convenient serving-size portions with everything you need to drink the beer built in. Open the can or bottle, and there is no step 2.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But&amp;#8230; what you drink beer from &lt;em&gt;does&lt;/em&gt; matter. Beer-focused bars offer a variety of glasses to accentuate the appearance and aromatics of a beer. Doesn&#39;t it seem just a little bit nicer when your beer comes in a stemmed glass instead of your standard pint glass?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When your beer is in the right glass, it can help open up subtleties that you may not have noticed in any other glass. If you&#39;d like to learn more about how this works, well good news, there&#39;s now a guide for that in the &lt;a href=&quot;/tasting/&quot;&gt;Tasting Library&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;a class=&quot;button button-large&quot; href=&quot;/tasting/choosing-glassware/&quot;&gt;All About Glassware&lt;/a&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 28 Aug 2016 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://palatedeck.com/2016/08/28/glassware.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://palatedeck.com/2016/08/28/glassware.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>All About Beer Styles</title>
        <description>&lt;img src=&quot;/images/photo-beer-flights.jpg&quot; class=&quot;blog-photo&quot; alt=&quot;Flights of different colours of beer&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pilsners, pale ales, stouts, saisons and lambics. There are hundreds of historical beer styles, not to mention the way modern breweries are evolving those and creating new ones all the time. Navigating beer styles can be tough without a guide.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&#39;ve ever been curious about the difference between a stout and a porter, or have never been quite sure what imperial means, there&#39;s help at hand. All these and more can be found in the &lt;a href=&quot;/tasting/beer-styles/&quot;&gt;Beer Styles&lt;/a&gt; reference, a new permanent addition to the &lt;a href=&quot;/tasting/&quot;&gt;Tasting Library&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;a class=&quot;button button-large&quot; href=&quot;/tasting/beer-styles/&quot;&gt;All About Beer Styles&lt;/a&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2016 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://palatedeck.com/2016/08/25/beerstyles.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://palatedeck.com/2016/08/25/beerstyles.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
